

about

Highly interested in Machine
Learning and Neuroscience.
Experienced with algorithms and data structures and a big fan of competitive programming.

skills

Pytorch, Tensorflow
Python, C
C++, C#, Java
Haskell, Scala
MATLAB, OpenCV

acomplishments

- Qualified to the ACM-ICPC
 Southeastern European Regional
 Contest as a 1st year student.
- Won 1st place in multiple college level contests and hackathons: Catalyst Coding Contest 2019, Textract 2018, ITFest 2017.
- Finalist in a National Olympiad every school year (mathematics, physics and informatics), obtaining medals and awards.

links

- <u>armandnicolicioiu.github.io</u>
- github.com/ArmandNM
- hackerrank.com/ArmandNM
- codeforces.com/profile/ArmandNM

Armand Nicolicioiu

AI ENTHUSIAST +40746900388 armand.nicolicioiu@gmail.com

education



Master in Artificial Intelligence

University of Bucharest (2020 - 2022)

• <u>Thesis</u>: Research in **out-of-distribution generalization** by **diversifying** Attention heads in **Vision Transformers**.



Bachelor in Computer Science and Engineering

Politehnica University of Bucharest (2015 - 2020)

• <u>Thesis</u>: Research in meta-learning and few-shot classification using Graph Neural Networks and Attention mechanisms.

work experience



Software Engineering Intern

Google, Zürich, Switzerland (June 2022 - September 2022)

- Used large language models to process the transcripts of YT videos.
- Generated realistic synthetic data to complement existing training sets.



Machine Learning Researcher

dotLumen, Cluj-Napoca, Romania (October 2020 - November 2021)

- Prototyped a headset to help blind persons be more independent.
- Multi-modal environment understanding using Computer Vision.



Software Engineering Intern

Microsoft, Redmond, WA, USA (July 2019 - September 2019)

- Designed and built a fast generic trending system for large scale data.
- Microservices pipeline for ingestion, processing, storing and retrieval.



Software Engineering Intern

Microsoft, Redmond, WA, USA (July 2018 - September 2018)

 Improved Azure's real-time telemetry monitoring system by generating recommendations that lead to a faster resolution of alerts.



Machine Learning and Computer Vision Junior Researcher

arnia Arnia Software, Bucharest (January 2017 - November 2017)

- Developed algorithms for improving the HDR camera mode of phones.
- Researched generic object segmentation and color perception.



Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Sparktech Software, Bucharest (July 2016 - October 2016)

• Built a recommender system for a coupon site from scratch.

I have two incoming research internships

aws Research Intern

Amazon, Tübingen, Germany (November 2022 - April 2023)

• With Florian Wenzel and Francesco Locatello on OOD generalization.



Research Intern

Idiap Research Institute, Martigny, Switzerland (starting May 2023)

• With Damien Teney on robustness of diversified models.

projects



Study on Topological Noise Invariant Features

International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR 2021)

- Improved the differential geometry and topology libraries Giotto-TDA and Geomstats during the Computational Geometry & Topology Challenge at ICLR.
- Our team won the **1st place** and we <u>co-authored the paper</u> summarizing the results.



Epileptic Sleep Study

Neuroscience Laboratory, "Carol Davila" University Bucharest

- Built ML models for epileptic seizure detection and sleep staging in mice.
- Created a semi-automated labeling tool for EEG & EMG signals.

conferences



Romanian Al Days

Oradea (Oct 2022), Virtual (2021)

- Received Best Poster award for my thesis on robustness and OOD generalization.
- Presented conclusions of ad-hoc team brainstorming during "unconference".



Synapse AI Symposium by Bending Spoons

Milan (Jul 2022)

• Scholarship awarded.



Eastern European Machine Learning Summer School (EEML)

Bucharest (July 2019), Virtual (2020, 2021)

- Received Best Poster award for my thesis on Meta-Learning for Few-Shot Learning (2020).
- Attended lectures and workshops held by experienced researchers from all across the globe.
- Acted as a volunteer in the preparation and during the school (2019).



Multi-Agent Systems and Learning Agents Summer School

AI-MAS Laboratory (June 2016)

- Introduction to the fields of machine learning and multi-agent systems.
- I won the contest for the best research idea.

teaching experience



Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Politehnica University of Bucharest (October 2016 - October 2021)

- TA for: Data Structures and Computer Programming classes.
- I taught laboratory classes and helped students solve the exercises.
- Prepared complex assignments for the entire class of 150 students.
- Proposed questions for the final exam and helped evaluating and grading.